[ Crowd Sounds ]
[人群声]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning, and welcome.
&gt;&gt; 早上好 欢迎大家来
My name is Jean-Gabriel.
我的名字叫 Jean-Gabriel
I hope you've been having a
希望大家这周
great week.
过的很愉快
We're here to talk about file
我们在这里要谈一谈
providers, the technology
File Provider 一项
between, behind the new Files
新文件 App  背后的
app.
技术
We're going to see what file
我们将会看到什么是
providers are and what new APIs
File Provider 以及 iOS 11 中
in iOS 11 allow you to enumerate
有哪些新的 API 可以让你
files from the cloud down to the
将文件从云端枚举至
device, to modify those files on
设备上
the device and up to the cloud,
在设备上修改文件并上传至云端
and to customize your file
也可以自定义你的 File Provider
provider to expose your
以便展示你的
non-standout features.
不突出的特性
So file providers have been
File Provider 在 iOS 8 时
around since iOS 8, and at the
就出现了 就其本质而言
core, they materialize files for
它们为各种应用程序
applications.
实体化文件
So applications may keep
所以 各应用程序可以
preferences to files that are
在 File Provider 的帮助下
provided by file providers, and
保持对文件的偏好设定
when they need the files, file
当它们需要这些文件时 File Provider
providers fulfill the promises.
就可以提供文件完成这项使命
But we are here today to talk
不过 我们今天要讲的是
about the new APIs, the APIs for
新的 API
enumerating files from the cloud
用来将文稿从云端枚举至设备
down to the device.
的 API
So the audience for this talk is
因此这次演讲的听众应该是
people who have servers out
拥有服务器
there with user documents on
并且服务器上有用户文稿
those servers and want to bring
并且想要将
those documents to iPad and
这些文稿移送至 iPad 和
iPhone.
iPhone 上的人
So let's look at the Files app.
我们来看一看文件 App
The Files app is a thin wrapper
文件 App  是
around a new piece of system UI
一个对新系统 UI 的瘦包装器
called the document browser that
它被称作文稿浏览器
is pretty ubiquitous in the
在系统中
system.
被普遍使用
It is where the user, where
这里是用户查询
users find, organize, share,
组织 分享
open documents.
打开文稿的地方
File providers appear here under
File Provider 就位于“位置”
Locations.
的下方
These are the entry points to
这里有你的云存储
your cloud storage, and iCloud
的入口点 而 iCloud Drive
Drive is one of them.
就是其中之一
That's good.
这很棒
That means that the APIs that we
这意味着我们今天要涉及的
are going to go through today
API 都是
are implemented by iCloud Drive,
经过 iCloud Drive 执行的
really well tested, and you have
已经通过了测试
a reference point if you're
你可以从中获得参考
wondering about the expected
如果你想知道
behavior of, say, renaming your
比如给你的的文件重命名为
file when there's already a file
相同文件夹下另一文件
with the same name and the same
的名字时会发生什么
folder, or you can just try it
你可以直接
out in iCloud Drive and see how
在 iCloud Drive 上试验
it's supposed to behave.
看看会出现怎样的情况
It also means that your
这也意味你的文稿
documents, being in a file
储存在类似 iCloud Drive
provider just like iCloud Drive,
的 File Provider 上时
are first-class citizens on the
是 OS 上的
OS.
“一等公民”
They're available everywhere
它们随处可得
really prominently just as
同 iCloud Drive 文稿一样
iCloud Drive documents.
突出
Actually, on this shot, iCloud
实际上 在这张屏幕快照中
Drive is at the top, but the
iCloud Drive 位于顶端
user may want to reconfigure
不过用户可以重新配置
that however they want to really
在 File Provider上
leave on your file provider.
只留下他们真正想要的
There's on file provider in
这就是关于
there that I just want to make a
File Provider 我顺便
passing mention of.
想提及的一点
On My iPad, that is the only
“我的 iPad”是唯一的
local file provider.
提供本地文件的
That is the only file provider
是唯一
that doesn't show files that are
不显示储存在云中的文件
in the cloud somewhere, and it's
的文件提供器
for apps to expose their
它让 App 向其他应用程序
document, their local document
显示其文稿
storage to other applications.
和本地储存的文稿
So let's see where the document
让我们看看
browser fits on the platform.
在这个平台上文稿浏览器所处的位置
Well, it sits right below the
它就位于基于文稿的应用程序
document-based applications --
下方
the Files app that we just saw;
就是我们刚刚看到的那些文件 App
all the iWork apps, which
比如全部的 iWork App
[inaudible] the document browser
它们也是新的系统 UI 上
to be that new piece of system
的一部分
UI; and all the third-party
所有 iOS 11 上的第三方
[inaudible] in iOS 11.
文件 App
On the other side of the
在文稿浏览器 UI
document browser UI are the file
的另一边就是
providers, and the file
File Provider
providers will provide files to
File Provider 将给系统 UI 提供文件
the system UI while the
而基于文稿的应用程序
document-based applications
则可以挑选
pick, open one of those
从某个 File Provider 中
documents from whichever file
打开其中的一个文稿
provider, edit, or create new
修改或者创建
documents.
新的文稿
So the reason why document-based
之所以
applications are going to adapt
基于文稿的应用程序现在需要
is that this is a single API to
进行适配 就是因为只有
get access to all the places
这唯一一个 API 能够访问
where their users have their
所有用户储存其文稿
documents.
的地方
Replaces the multiple SDKs that
替换目前
they have had to adapt to until
必须适配多个 SDK
now.
的情况
The reasons for file providers
File Provider 需要适配
to adopt is the privacy model,
是因为它的隐私模式
which is really awesome here.
这个非常棒
So document-based applications
这样基于文稿的应用程序
open documents one at a time.
一次打开的一个文稿
It's totally user-gated access.
完全是用户配置的访问
The system UI is out of process.
系统 UI 是在进程外的
Document-based applications
基于文稿的应用程序
cannot know which files exist
无法得知其选定的文件
next to the file that was picked
旁的其它文件是什么
or even which file providers are
甚至在用户选定文稿前
installed until the user picks
都不知道
one of the documents.
安装了哪些 File Provider
There are two key APIs here:
这里有两个关键的 API
UIDocumentBrowser
UIDocumentBrowser
ViewController, which is in the
和 ViewController
SDK of the document-based
二者都是基于文稿应用程序
applications, and
的 SDK 还有
NSFileProviderExtension.
NSFileProviderExtension
We're not here to talk about
我们今天不讲
UIDocumentBrowser
UIDocumentBrowser
ViewController.
和 ViewController
That was covered in the session
这两个在昨天会议中已经讲过了
yesterday that I invite you to
如果你错过了关于
go watch if you missed it about
构建基于文稿应用程序
building document-based
的讲座的话
applications.
我建议你去看看视频
We are here to talk about the
我们今天要讲的是
other end of this,
另一端
NSFileProviderExtension.
也就是 NSFileProviderExtension
So let's look again at the Files
我们再看一下
app.
文件 App
There are two main ways for the
用户访问
user to go and interact with his
并同文稿进行互动有
documents, and those correspond
两个主要的方法 对应着
to two tabs in the app.
应用程序上的两个标签
The first tab is the Browse tab.
第一个标签是“浏览”标签
That is where the user goes to
在这里 用户
find content in your cloud and
可以在你的云端搜索内容
bring it down to the device.
并将其下载至设备上
In this mode, your file provider
在这个模式下 你的 File Provider 扩展
extension acts as a pipe between
如同管道一般
the system UI and your servers.
连接着系统 UI 和你的服务器
It's not even expected to work
事实上也不期望它
offline, really.
在离线的环境下工作
Once the user has selected those
一旦用户在“浏览”标签
documents in the Browse tab,
选择过文稿后
they become available in the
这些被选择的文稿也就会出现在
Recents tab.
“最近”标签中
The Recents tab is the other
“最近”标签是另一种
mode, and it is a flat list of
模式 它是一个文稿的扁平列表
documents that come from the
列表中的文稿都
very sources of documents and
同原文稿的来源相同
are really relevant to the user.
和用户极具相关性
That is where the user is going
这里就是用户
to go look for the file he wants
可以查找他想要打开的文件
to open.
的地方
And sure enough, it's going to
当然了 文件一定会
be there.
出现在那里
So two tabs -- Browse, Recents.
所以 我们提到两个栏标“浏览”和“最近”
The Browse tab is for putting
所以“浏览”标签是用来
new content for file providers
给 File Provider 提供新内容的
online for, folder, online to
提供至线上文件夹中
folders and pick a document.
然后选取文稿
The Recents tab shows what we
而“最近”标签则是用来显示
call the working set, and we're
工作集的
going to talk about the working
我们现在就来谈谈
set now.
工作集
So it's not folder based and it
它不是基于文件夹的
spans multiple file providers.
而且横跨多个 File Provider
And in a working set, there are
在一个工作集中
these documents.
有这些文稿
So recently-opened documents or
最近打开的文稿
used document, favorites, tag
最近使用过的文稿 收藏过的 加过标签的文稿
documents and folders, documents
和文件夹 通过或者由用户
shared through or by the user,
分享过的文稿
documents that were previously
先前下载到设备上
downloaded to the device and are
可以离线获取的
available offline, and
文稿
recently-deleted documents.
以及近期删除的文稿
For the user experience to be
为了在不同的 File Provider 之间
consistent across file provider,
确保用户体验能够保持一致
we ask you to put all those
我们要求你
files in the working set.
把这些文件都放在工作集中
But you have domain-specific
当然 各位对于特定领域
knowledge.
的了解更多
You know what's relevant to the
知道哪些是与用户
user.
相关的
So you might choose to add more
如果需要的话
to the working set, if you so
各位可以选择在工作集中
want.
加入更多
However, caveat: We are actually
不过 要给大家提个醒：我们其实
Smart Caching the working set on
会对设备上的工作集
the device.
进行 Smart Caching （智能快取）
So once something is in the
所以 一旦某些东西加进了
working set, you'll have to keep
工作集中 你就必须
it in sync.
保证其同步
I'll get back to that.
我之后也会再谈到这点
So in the document browser in
在“最近”标签的
the Recents tab, you'll see the
文稿浏览器中 各位可以找到
working set.
工作集
And each file provider may
每个 File Provider 都有可能
contribute different documents
向工作集中
to the working set.
提供不同的文稿
We don't do that at display
我们就不在这里
time.
演示了
If we had to merge the list of
在我们合并文稿列表时
documents as they come in from
因为文稿都来自于
the different file provider
不同的 File Provider 扩展
extensions when the UI is
所以当在 UI 上显示的时候
onscreen, you'd have weird
就会出现奇怪的动画模拟效果
animations, visual glitches.
绘制上的小错误
So we don't do that.
所以 我们不这么做
Instead, what we do is we
我们要做的是
enumerate a working set index
枚举一个工作集的索引
that is kept by the system when
在 UI 出现时
the UI comes up.
这一工作集的索引被保存在系统中
And your file provider
而你的
extensions are not even invoked
File Provider 扩展
at all.
甚至都没有被启用
We're going to talk about how
我们要谈谈 这一索引
that index is built.
是如何构建的
So the index is local and on the
索引是本地的
device.
位于设备上的
It is the aggregation of the
它是由来自不同 File Provider 的
working set from the different
工作集
file providers.
汇聚而成的
Because the index is local, it
因为索引是本地的
means the index is available
这就意味着它
offline.
支持离线使用
It means that offline, if I
这就意味着 在离线时
bring up that UI, the document
如果我启动 UI 文稿浏览器
browser, I will see my recent
我就能够看到
documents.
我的近期文稿
That doesn't mean that all the
当然 这不是说所有的文稿在所有时间里都
documents are local on the
在本地设备上
device at all time and offline.
能够离线访问
It means that [inaudible] to
但这意味着构建起的 UI
build the UI is cached to the
的很多文稿已经缓存
device.
到了设备上
Because the index is local and
因为索引处于本地
available offline, it is also in
并可以离线访问
Spotlight.
所以它也出现在 Spotlight 中
So the system index is for you,
在系统索引的帮助下
the working set in Spotlight,
工作集会出现在 Spotlight 中
and users may pick a document in
而用户就可以在 Spotlight 中选取
Spotlight, and that will wake
一个文稿 而此时你的
your file provider extension at
File Provider 扩展
that time.
也就会被唤醒
So let's talk about how you
接下来我们看看
provide files to the working set
如何向工作集索引提供文稿
index, which happens in the
这个过程在后台进行
background before the document
发生在文稿浏览器
browser comes up.
运行之前
The first thing that you are
你要做的第一件事
going to have to do is sync your
就是必须将你的工作集
working set from your servers
从服务器上同步至
down to the device.
设备上
So watch those file provider
仔细看那些
extension boxes here.
File Provider 扩展框
The, we're asking you to keep a
我们要求你
database of the metadata for all
为在设备上的工作集中的所有文件
the files in the working set on
保存一个
the device.
包含元数据的数据库
And actually, do sync both ways
实际上 两个方向都应该同步
because there are local changes
因为本地
and [inaudible] changes.
和远程都会有变更出现
The second step is that the
第二步 系统将会
working set, the system is going
从你的 File Provider 中
to drive the enumeration of the
对工作集进行枚举
working set from your file
以此
providers to build the index.
来生成索引
Happens in the background.
这些都发生在后台
And then at a later time, when
稍后 当 UI 出现时
the UI comes up, the system will
系统将会枚举你的
enumerate the working set index
工作集索引 在文稿浏览器中显示“最近”
without waking your file
而不会
provider extension to show the
唤醒你的
Recents in the document browser.
File Provider 扩展
All right, we're asking you to
好吧 我们要求
do a lot of things here.
各位做的事情还不少
We're asking you do sync and to
我们要求大家进行同步
do sync of a partial set of your
将部分文稿
documents.
进行同步
If you can't do partial sync,
如果你不进行部分同步的话
you might want to consider
可能就要
syncing all the user's documents
将用户的所有文稿
down to the device.
都同步到设备上
You're going to hit scaling
你可能就会遇到
issues, so think carefully about
规模化问题
what you do there.
所以一定要考虑清楚再进行操作
OK, what we saw to this point is
目前为止
that there are two ways to
我们讲了两种浏览文稿
browse documents.
的方法
There is a Recents tab that
“最近”标签可以
shows the working set, which is
显示工作集
synced in the background to the
它在后台同步至设备上
device, and there is a Browse
还有“浏览”标签
tab, which is based on the
它是基于
online enumerations of folders.
对文件夹的线上枚举
And I'm going to call Pierre to
接下来 我要请 Pierre
show you how to create a file
来给大家展示
provider extension now.
如何创建一个 File Provider 扩展
Thank you, Pierre.
谢谢 Pierre
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Jean-Gabriel.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Jean-Gabriel
So let's talk about creating a
我们来看看如何
file provider extension.
创建一个 File Provider 扩展
First, we're going to see how to
首先 我们要看看如何
create the project, then how to
先创建一个项目 然后是如何
provide a single item, then
提供一个单一条目 如何
enumerate a list of items, and
枚举一系列的条目
then I will [inaudible] was
然后
going to go through you, with
我会和大家一起
you an [inaudible] to modify
看看如何修改这些条目
item, provide custom action, and
提供自定义操作
as well as do something very,
以及一项十分强大的功能
very powerful, which is provide
就是向第三方应用程序
services to third-parties.
提供服务
What does that mean?
这意味着什么呢
It means that your file provider
这意味着你的 File Provider 扩展
extension can provide its own
能够提供其自有的 API
API, so you own API to other
也就是你自己的 API
third-party's app.
给其它的第三方 App
This is really cool, so you
这个功能棒极了
probably want to stay until you
大家现在都该留下听我讲
see this or play it online
或者回去后
later.
在网上看看这个视频
Creating a file provider
从头创建一个
extension is really simple if
File Provider 扩展
you start from scratch.
十分简单
So there is a Xcode template,
这是一个 Xcode 模板
File Provider Extension.
File Provider Extension
Just click on it.
只要点击一下它
Boom, it's done.
一下就完成了
And then the real work begin.
然后我们开始真正的工作
You have to subclass
你需要将 NSFileProviderExtension
NSFileProviderExtension.
加入子类别
If you already have an existing
如果你已经有了一个
file provider extension, in that
File Provider 扩展
case, what you should do is add
在这种情况下
the support enumeration key to
你应该将支持的枚举 Key
your Info.plist.
加入到你的 info.plist
That will tell the system, look,
这就相当于你告知系统
you probably want to take this
你想要用这个文件扩展
file extension and use the new
并且使用新的 UI
UI to render my document.
来打开文稿
So the big picture during this
这就是你应该
file provider extension subclass
创建的 File Provider 扩展子类别
that you should build.
的主要部分
Your file provider extension
你的 File Provider 扩展子类别
subclass [inaudible] is to vend
将会发送
the item metadata by
条目元数据
implementing or returning object
需要你执行
implementing the NSFileProvider
NSFileProvider 协议和
protocol, NSFileProviderItem
NSFileProviderItem
protocol.
协议
Those item are identified by a
那些条目将会通过
string that you provide and are
你提供的字符串被识别
materialized on disk through
然后通过文件网址
file URL.
实体化在磁盘上
The folder contents of your file
你的 File Provider 的
provider is exposed by
文件夹内容是通过执行
implementing what we call an
NSFileProviderEnumerator
NSFileProviderEnumerator.
来显示的
That sounds complicated, but
这个听起来很复杂
it's not.
其实不然
So, and before jumping into the
在我们细致讲解之前
very detail, let's have a big
我们先看一下手头需要完成的
picture of the tasks we've been
任务的大框架
going through and see what the
在我们创建这些后
anatomy of a file provider
看一下
extension is going to look like
File Provider 扩展的结构
after we build all this.
将会是如何的
So first task, we need to
第一项任务 我们需要为
provide the metadata for a given
一个特定的条目标识符
item identifier.
提供元数据
That's straightforward if you
如果你有数据库的话
have a database, so you probably
这个操作就很简单
want to have a database.
所以 有一个数据库能帮你很多
Then, you need to map URLs to
然后 你需要将网址映射到
item identifiers.
条目表标识符
That's probably a semicolon in
这可能是
your database.
你的数据库中的一个分号
Last, you're in charge of
最后 你需要负责
managing the disk storage,
管理磁盘储存
whether the data corresponding
不论文稿对应的数据是
to a file is local or not.
本地的还是线上的
That's the second piece of your
这个是 File Provider 扩展
file provider extension.
的第二部分
And inside the disk storage, of
在磁盘储存中
course, file can be there or
当然 文件可能在这里
not, as [inaudible].
也可能不在
OK, so we've seen the anatomy.
好的 我们已经看过基本的结构了
Let's jump in and provide an
接下来看看如何
item.
提供一个条目
item?
是什么意思呢
First, you need to provide a
首先 你需要提供一个
file URL.
文件网址
Then, file contents, metadata,
然后为你的条目提供
and thumbnail for your item.
文件内容 元数据和缩略图
That's it.
这就是你需要做的
Why do you need to provide a
你可能会问
file URL, you might ask?
我该怎么样提供一个文件网址呢
Well, file provider manipulates
File Provider 可以直接操控
file provider item and file
File Provider 条目
provider item identifier, not
和 File Provider 条目标识符
file URLs directly.
但是不能直接操控文件网址
However, document-based apps do
但是 基于文稿的 App
consume file URLs, so we need to
需要文件网址 所以我们需要
bridge between the two, so let's
在二者间建立连接
take an example.
我们举个例子
When the user taps on the file
当用户在文件 App  中轻按一个文件时
in the File app, the File app
文件 App  此时
only has access to your item
只能访问
identifier at that point.
你的条目标识符
So before calling the
所以
document-based app, it's
在调用基于文稿的 App 前
actually going to call into your
首先需要
file provider extension
调用你的
subclass.
File Provider 扩展分类别
The method urlForItem with
带有标识符的 urlForItem
identifier is going to get
会被调用
called, and so you will look in
然后你需要在你的数据库中查找
your database, figure out the
找到特定条目标识符
URL for the given item
的网址
identifier, and, boom, you'll
然后你将会
return into the document-based
返回到
app.
基于文稿的 App 中去
Not sure if the system does it
我不太确定系统会不会
for you, but you [inaudible] to
帮你完成这项操作
the system which items to the
不过你可以告知系统
document-based app, and you're
基于文稿的 App 需要哪些条目
done.
然后这一步就完成了
At that point, the
此时
document-based app opened a file
基于文稿的 App 通过网址
by URL.
打开一个文件
On the other [inaudible], I was
我之前讲过了
talking about the database to
数据库网址和
the URL to item identifier
条目标识符映射
mapping.
相关的东西
One thing you might want to do
我建议你
is to actually start the item
在文件网址中
identifier inside the file URL.
添加条目标识符
It's very convenient because you
这样的话就会提供很多便利
can avoid database lookup if you
你可以不用进行数据库查找
do that and you can tag items
也可以在重命名文件中
between renames.
跟踪条目
Last tidbit, you probably want
另外 你也最好
to keep a flat list in your disk
在磁盘储存中
storage.
保存一个扁平列表
You don't need to replicate the
这样你就不需要复制
folder hierarchy because this is
文件夹的层次结构
quite complicated, and so you
这个还是很复杂的
can avoid it, so please do.
所以你最好还是保存一个扁平列表
So you might say, hey, Pierre,
可能你会问 Pierre
so we have the file URL, but
我们现在有了文件网址
what about the file content?
那文件内容怎么办呢
Because I did not know they're
因为我们之前不知道
missing at that point.
它们到现在这个阶段还没出现呢
So of course, we should look
当然
into that.
我们这就来看这一点
So you can open the file by, so
当基于文稿的应用程序
when the document-based app
打开你的文件时
opened your app, it opened the
它是通过网址
file by URL.
来打开文件的
But it's not doing that state.
但是 它不是直接进行的
Like, it should use
它会使用
NSFileCoordinator and read using
NSFileCoordinator 然后使用文件协调请求
a file coordination request.
来读取
That is something apps using UI
这是 App 可以免费
documents do for free, so when
使用的 UI 文稿
that happens, your file provider
然后 你的 File Provider 扩展
extension is called.
就会被调用
Most specifically, in your
明确的说
subclass, startProvidingItem at
在你的子类别中
URL with completionHandler is
带有 completionHandler 的网址的
going to get called.
startProvidingItem 将会被调用
When you [inaudible], you look
然后 你查看
into your disk storage.
你自己的磁盘储存
You figure out the item is not
发现条目
there.
并不在那里
So you go in your server,
然后你去服务器那里
NSURLSession most likely, and
最有可能是使用 NSURLSession
you download the file.
把文件下载下来
The download completes.
下载完成
The file is moved into your disk
文件就移动到
storage.
你的磁盘储存中了
Now, you can call the
现在 你可以调用
completionHandler that is going
completionHandler 它帮你
to grant the coordination to the
为基于文稿的 App 提供
document-based app.
NSFileCoodination
And at that point, the file is
然后
opened.
就可以打开文件了
Cool. So what happens if you
如果你下一次又有需要时
want this a second time?
会发生什么呢
Because this time, the file is
因为这次的时候
there.
文件就已经在那里了
But there is still going to be a
不过 还是需要
file coordinator reader request
发送一个
issued.
文件协调读取请求
And at that point, this is
到目前为止
pretty cool.
一切都很顺利
Your file provider extension
你的
subclass is going to get called
File Provider 扩展子类别
again.
将再次被调用
So that's very powerful for you
这个功能很强大
to track usage on your files.
你就可以跟踪文件的使用
But this time, the file is here,
但是这次 文件已经在这里了
so what do you need to do?
你需要怎么做呢
Well, you just
你只要
completionHandler, and you're
使用 completionHandler
done.
就可以了
It's very powerful, but at the
这个很强大
same time, it means that your
不过同时 这意味着你的
file provider extension might
File Provider 扩展
be, might delay file loading.
有可能减慢文件的加载速度
So you better be fast when you
所以 如果你的文件已经在本地
implement startProvidingItem if
你要应用程序 startProvidingItem
the file is already local.
你的速度最好够快
OK, so the coordination is
接着 NSFileCoordination
granted, and you've seen this
被授权 这点你们刚才已经
before.
看过了
The file is now opened.
现在文件就被打开了
Second part.
第二部分
In the Files app, the metadata
在文件 App 中 文件的元数据
of your files are prominent.
是十分重要的
And the way it works is that for
其运作方法是这样的：
each item that the files have
对于文件所展示的每一个条目
displayed, your file provider is
你的 File Provider 都会
going to be called, and the
被调用
specific method this time is
更精确的说 这次要用的方法
called item for itemIdentifier,
叫做 itemIdentifier
which returned an
它可以
NSFileProviderItem.
传回一个 NSFileProviderItem
That item should be [inaudible]
这个条目
from your database.
应该从你的数据库中获取
So you look at your database,
在数据库中
you get an NSFileProviderItem,
你获得 NSFileProviderItem
and you return it.
然后你将其传回
OK, that was simple, but I did
这个听起来很简单
not actually go into the detail
不过我还没有讲到细节部分
of what is an
到底什么是
NSFileProviderItem.
NSFileProviderItem 呢
So as I told you a bit earlier,
其实就像我刚才说过的
it's a protocol.
它就是个协议
And with most protocol, you have
像大多数协议一样
required properties as well as
它有必填属性和
optional properties.
可选属性
So let's go into the detail of
我们先详细讲一下
the required properties that
必填属性
your object conforming to
这是你的对象适配
NSFileProviderItem must
NSFileProviderItem
implement.
必须要应用到的
So the first properties are
第一个属性一般是
usually the itemIdentifier, so
itemIdentifier
that's a simple string.
一个简单的字符串
Then, you have the
然后是
typeIdentifier, and that is the
typeIdentifier 这是一个 UTI
UTI, indicating whether the file
表明文件是
is a PDF, an image, or a folder.
一个 PDF 文件 一个图像或是一个文件夹
And last but not least, you have
最后一项要点
the filename, which is pretty
是 Filename
prominent in [inaudible] UI.
它在 UI 中很重要
So now that we've seen the
现在我们已经讲完
required properties, that's all
必要属性
you really need to implement, we
这些都是你需要使用的
can move on to the optional
我们可以继续讲可选属性
properties that we strongly
我们强烈
encourage you to also implement.
建议大家也要应用
For instance, in this particular
比如
screenshot here, there is the
在这张屏幕快照上
shared status that is displayed
在文件名的下面
just below the filename.
清楚的显示了其分享的状态
That shared status is displayed
如果你设置了 isShared 属性的话
onscreen if you set the isShared
这一分享状态
property.
就会显示出来
And to go along with the shared
和分享状态一起的
status, you have the
你也可以使用 ownerNameComponents
ownerNameComponents that you can
来更加
specify.
明确地显示
And now, you can see on my
现在 你们就能在我的
document slide, "Shared by
幻灯片上看到
Amaury," which is pretty good to
“由 Amaury 分享”,
know.
知道这个信息还是很棒的
Then, you have additional states
此外 你还可以添加其它的状态
such as isDownloaded -- that
比如 isDownloaded
lets, display a small down arrow
这样就会出现一个小的向下的箭头
-- isUploading and uploadError.
还有 isUploading 和 uploadError
So the uploadError is
uploadError 很有意思
interesting because if your user
如果你的用户实际上
doesn't have enough [inaudible]
无法上传文件
to actually upload the file, you
你可能不会
probably won't position that
定位
error.
这个错误
OK, there are a lot of
我们已经看到了
additional properties.
很多额外的属性
Unfortunately, we don't have
遗憾的是
time to go through all of them.
我们没有时间去浏览全部的属性
So we're just going to move on,
我们继续讲下去
but I encourage you to read our
不过我建议大家读一下我们的文稿
documentation, which is pretty
里面有关于这个主题
good on the subject, as well as
的详尽解释
our header files.
以及我们的头文件
Well, so we've seen the
我们已经谈过
metadata, but there is one last
元数据
piece of metadata we did not
不过其中还有一点是我们没有讲到的
talk about, and it's a fairly
还是很重要的一点
big one, so it used a different
它使用的是一个不同的
pipeline.
传输途径
It's the thumbnail.
它就是缩略图
So when the Files app displays
当文件 App 显示
your file, especially if the
你的文件时 尤其是
file is not local -- in that
那些本地文件 在这种情况下
case, there is no way we can
我们不可能
generate a thumbnail out of that
为文件生成一个缩略图
file -- what we are going to do
需要进行的操作就是
is to ask your file provider
让 File Provider 扩展
extension to fetch the
抓取一系列文件
thumbnails for a list of files.
的缩略图
In that case, you can go on your
这样 你就可以去服务器中
server, ask it to download the
请求下载
thumbnail associated to the
和文件相关的
file.
缩略图
When the download completes, you
当下载完成后
hand back the thumbnail data.
你就可以传回缩略图数据
And at this point, we just
这样
display the thumbnail.
就可以显示缩略图了
So I'm going to go into detail
接下来 我要详细讲讲
of how that fetch thumbnail
抓取缩略图的原理
function works because it's a
这个功能相对于
bit more involved than the other
其它的功能而言
one.
更复杂一些
So first, what you have onscreen
首先 屏幕上显示的是
if your file provider extension
File Provider 扩展
subclass.
子类别
And so we did, it's a file
这个 File Provider 扩展
provider extension subclass
子类别叫做
called MyFileProviderExtension.
MyFileProviderExtension
And there, you want to override
然后 如果你要
the fetchThumbnail function.
覆盖 fetchThumbnail 功能
It takes a list of item
需要一系列的
identifiers.
条目标识符
Why a list?
为什么是一系列呢
Because we want to do batching
因为出于性能的考虑
for performance reasons so that
我们想要批量的处理
we don't [inaudible] the server
这样就不需要为了每个缩略图
for every thumbnail.
去访问服务器了
Then, you have a requestedSize,
然后是 requestedSize
a perThumbnailCompletionHandler,
perThumbnailCompletionHandler
and then an overall
和一个整体的
completionHandler.
completionHandler
The first thing you want to do
你要做的第一件事
is to actually create a progress
其实是要创建一个
object.
Progress 对象
The reason why is not so much
创建这个并不
for reporting, but more for
完全是出于报告的考虑
consideration purposes so that
而是在当
if the thumbnail request is
缩略图请求被取消时
canceled because the user
比如当用户不再使用文件 App 的时候
dismissed the Files app, then
你就能够了解到这一情况
you would be aware and you would
然后就可以
be able -- and you must,
或者说就必须要
actually -- cancel your
取消掉
thumbnail request.
你的缩略图请求
So now, imagine you download the
现在 想象你使用下载任务
files from your server using a
从服务器上
download task.
下载了文件
For each thumbnail, you get the
对于每一个缩略图
file UI that you would have
你都有已经下载到的文件 UI
downloaded and you map it.
然后你对其进行映射操作
So be sure to not allocate
在这里一定不要
memory there.
分配内存
So I encourage you to use the
所以 我建议使用
alwaysMapped option.
alwaysMapped  选项
Finally, you call your
最后 你调用
perThumbnailCompletionHandler,
perThumbnailCompletionHandler
and that's not the real finally,
其实这个不是最后一步
the real finally is this one.
真正的最后一步是这个
You actually call the overall
你调用整体的
completionHandler.
completionHandler
So remember one thing: You must
要记住一件事 不论是在
call it in case of success,
成功 失败 还是取消的情况下
failure, cancellation always.
你都需要调用它
And now, you can return the
现在你就可以回传
progress object so that the
progress 对象 然后系统
system knows how to cancel your
就能够取消你的
thumbnail request.
缩略图请求了
Boom, well done.
干得不错
We provided an item, so we're
现在我们已经知道了
happy.
如何提供一个条目
But now, let's move on to the
接下来 我们继续讲下一个话题
next topic, which is enumerating
就是如何枚举
items.
条目
So for that, enumerating items
枚举条目
means actually providing data to
就是向我屏幕快照上的文件 App
the screenshots or to the Files
提供数据
app that I have on screenshot
就像我这张屏幕快照上
beside me.
显示的
And we are going to see how to
接下来我们要看看如何
paginate items, sync changes,
给条目标页数 同步变更
render push notification, and
进行推送通知
then signal changes.
还有标志变更
So enumerating item works this
枚举条目是
way.
这样进行的
The Files app starts up,
文件 App 启动
requests a page of item.
请求一页的条目
Your file provider extension
你的 File Provider 扩展
return the first page.
传回第一页
It's all over.
然后就结束了
There's still some room
屏幕上还有些空间
onscreen, so it's going to ask
就继续
for another page.
再请求一页
And so on and so forth until it
就这样反复运作
does everything.
直到完成所有的
The question you might ask is,
你可能会问
why do we paginate?
我们为什么要标页数呢
What's the sense of all this?
这些到底是为了干什么呢
So what you have to know is that
你需要了解
your extension is granted a tiny
你的扩展只被授予你的应用程序
fraction of the memory your app
被授予内存中的
is granted.
一小部分
If your app is in blue there,
如果你的应用程序被授予的内存是这里显示的蓝色部分
your extension is in gray.
你的扩展只是这小小的灰色部分
You can't even see it onscreen.
你甚至在屏幕上都看不到它
What you also have to know is
你需要注意
that above this limit of, if you
在这个限制下
allocate more memory than what
如果你分配的内存
you have available, your
超过你拥有的
extension is terminated.
你的扩展将会被终止
So we strongly encourage you --
所以 我们强烈建议你
and this is what pagination is
这就是为什么要进行标页数
all about -- to avoid peak in
的原因 就是要防止
your memory allocation.
你的内存分配达到峰值
I just want to go through some
我接下来想要讲几个
other tips that we found useful
小贴士 我们觉得很有用
and that you might also find
也希望你们
useful.
也能从中受益
Avoid using all data task.
不要使用 URLSessionDataTask
Instead, prefer the download and
最好用 URLSessionDownloadTask 和
upload task because they
URLSessionUploadTask
manipulate files, so they don't
因为它们可以操控文件
require memory allocation.
所以它们就不需要内存分配了
Use dispatch queues with an
使用 DispatchQueue
autorelease frequency of always.
autoreleaseFrequency 为 always
Otherwise, you can get memory
不然的话 你的内存将达峰值
peak due to too many allocation
因为有太多的内存分配到了
in your autorelease pool.
你的自动释放池中
And finally, as always, if you
最后
have a long running while or for
如果有循环的话
loop, be sure to [inaudible] to
记住要使用
autorelease [inaudible].
« while () @autoreleasepool {} »
So in any case, we don't have
我们没有时间
time to go into more details, so
去讲更多的细节了
check out this super session
所以 大家可以
from a while back, and there are
之后来看看这一部分的内容
some other you can probably
网上也有不少
check out online.
大家可以稍后查看
OK, let's go back to enumerating
我们返回到枚举条目
items.
这一部分
So on your Files app, you've
在你的文件 App 上
opened a folder.
你已经打开了一个文件夹
And it's going to call your file
这将会调用你的
provider extension subclass and
File Provider 扩展子类别
ask you to provide an enumerator
然后要求你为一个特定的条目标识符
for a given item identifier.
提供一个枚举器
On waving [phonetic], you will
然后
locate your NSFileProvider
你将定位你的 NSFileProvider
enumerator and return it to us.
枚举器 然后传回给我们
The Files app is going to store
文件 App 将会储存这个
that enumerator.
枚举器
And the next thing it's going to
下一步 就是
do is to ask you to provide the
要求你提供
initial page of item.
条目的 initialPage
You get a callback on your
这次在你的枚举器上
enumerator this time, which is
你收到一个回调函数
called enumerateItems for
叫做 enumerateItems
observer, startingAt page.
(for observer: ,startingAt page:)
You figure out the items in your
你找到
first page.
第一页上的条目
You return them.
你将其传回
And you say, you're done
然后 枚举的操作
enumerating.
就完成了
There is my second page.
这里是我的第二页
Well done.
不错
We've enumerated a page.
我们已经枚举了一页
If the file is [inaudible] to
如果文件有
have more items, it will
更多的条目的话
continue the, it will ask you
这样的流程会继续进行
for more pages using the exact
它会要求你通过同样的机制
same mechanism.
提供更多页
Let's go through the different
我们来回顾一下
methods we've seen.
刚刚讲过的不同的方法
So first method is in your
第一个方法
subclass of
在你的 NSFileProviderExtension
NSFileProviderExtension.
的子类别中
It's called enumerator
叫做
forContainer itemIdentifier, and
enumerator forContainer itemIdentifier
it returns an object conforming
然后它返回一个符合
to NSFileProviderEnumerator.
NSFileProviderEnumerator 的对象
The itemIdentifier can be one of
itemIdentifier 可以是以下的某一个
workingSet if we're enumerating
工作集 如果是枚举“最近”的话
the Recents, as Jean-Gabriel was
刚才 Jean-Gabriel 已经
describing earlier, or the
讲过了
rootContainer.
或者是 rootContainer
Finally, it can also be any of
最后 它也可能是你的文件夹中
your folder item identifiers
任何你之前回传过的
that you've previously returned.
条目标识符
The other function that we saw
另外一个
is this time on
功能是在
NSFileProviderEnumerator.
NSFileProviderEnumerator 上
It's enumerateItems for
就是 enumerateItems for
observer, startingAt page.
Observer 直接按照 page 枚举
The observer is a system, as we
Observer 是一个系统对象
saw earlier, is a system object
我们刚刚看到了
presenting, receiving your items
是一个显示 接收你的条目和下一页的
and the next page.
系统对象
The page is a simple data blob.
而 page 是一个简单的 Blob 数据
It has a type, but it's a simple
它有其类型 不过还是
data blob that you're free to
一个简单的 Blob 数据
decide what's, and you're free
你可以自由
to decide what's inside, as long
决定其中所包含的
as it doesn't go below 500
只要不超过 500
bytes.
字节就可以
What you generally put there is
一般放在里面的
like a page index -- 1, 2, 3, 4,
就是页的索引 1 2 3 4 5
5 -- or an item of sets
或者
[inaudible] et cetera.
是其它类似的
For the first page, it can be
对于第一页来说
one of any initial page sorted
它可以是按照日期或者名字排列
by date or sorted by name,
的任何首页
depending on what the UI is
取决于 UI
displaying.
的展示
OK, so let's go back to this
我们返回到
slide that you've seen before.
你们刚才看过的这张幻灯片
One crucial thing we've just
我们刚刚加的
added is the ability to
至关重要的一点
enumerate folders and the
就是枚举文件夹和
working set.
工作集
So we have two kinds of
我们有两种
enumerator, of enumerators, as
枚举器
you can see onscreen.
正如你在屏幕上看到的
And I just want to go back -- or
我现在想要退回来讲一下
actually, highlight the
其实是要重点说明一下
differences between the two.
这两类的区别所在
So for folder enumerator, what
对于文件夹枚举器
you typically do is enumerate
一般都是直接
the cloud directly.
枚举云端数据
That's it.
就像这样
You can do caching, however, if
如果想要的话
you want.
你可以进行缓存
It's up to you.
这个取决于你
You decide.
你自己决定
However, for the working set,
但是 工作集枚举器
it's very different.
就很不一样了
You need to enumerate your own
你需要枚举
local copy of the working set.
本地工作集的拷贝
So not the cloud.
而不是云端数据
Just your working set.
只是你的工作集
The main reason for that is that
主要原因 是因为
your working set must work
你的工作集必须
offline.
能够离线运行
The item is the working set, in
这个条目就是工作集
the working set must be
而工作集必须能够
available offline and work
离线访问也能够
offline.
离线运行
I just want to reiterate on this
我想要再
because this is something that
重复一下 因为有些点
is not obvious.
可能并不是显而易见的
So I'll say it again.
我再重复一下
The working set should never
工作集枚举器 一定不能
read the cloud.
读取云数据
The folder enumerator, it's OK.
而文件夹枚举器是可以的
And the working set should
然后工作集枚举器一定需要
always read the database, and
读取数据库
the folders, it's OK if you want
对于文件夹枚举器如果你想要
to cache them.
缓存它们的话也可以
It's fine.
就是这样
I hope it's clear.
我希望大家听明白了
Now, let's move on to the next
我们接着讲下一个话题
topic, which is syncing changes.
同步变更
So for that, on your cloud
在你的云服务器上
server, you are probably doing
你估计也需要进行
it anyway, but you need to
同步变更 但是你需要
assign version numbers to your
给你的条目
items.
分配版本编号
So here are some version numbers
这些是在我云服务器上的
on my [inaudible] cloud.
版本编号
The maximum known version number
最大的已知版本编号
is what we call the sync anchor.
我们叫做同步锚
So here it's 14.
这里最大的是 14
On changes, you need to bump the
在有变更出现时
file version number.
你需要增加版本编号
So here, for instance, 15.
比如 现在是 15
The count sync anchor -- oh, I
此时的同步锚
went a bit fast, but it's OK.
我进行的有些快了 不过也可以
I did a new file, which is,
我增加了一个新文件
which gave the version number
其版本编号是
And this time, we bumped the
这次 我们将
sync anchor to 16.
同步锚增加至 16
And remember, it was 13 at the
记住 第一开始 它是 13（口误 应为 14）
beginning, and then I went a bit
然后我进行了操作
fast, but you can see that now.
现在你能看到结果了
Then, if you, if we go back to
现在 如果你
the Files app in your file
回到在你的 File Provider 扩展
provider extension enumerator,
枚举器的文件 App 中去
what is going to happen -- and I
会发生什么呢
lied to you earlier.
我之前向你们撒了谎
Before enumerating, what we are
在枚举之前
going to do is to ask your
我们需要要求你的
enumerator to provide its
枚举器 提供其当前的
current sync anchor.
同步锚
So that's before enumerating the
这是在枚举
pages.
页之前的操作
So this [inaudible] you just
这样 你先得到
have your sync anchor.
你的同步锚
You return it back to the Files
然后你将其传回到文件 App
app, and the Files app is going
然后文件 App 就会
to store it.
将其储存
After that, we'll just fetch the
之后 我们就能够像刚才一样
pages as we did before, and
抓取页
we're in sync.
就可以同步了
When a new file is added on your
当一个新文件添加到你的服务器时
server, you add a new file here
你添加一个新文件
in green, you bump your sync
就是这个绿色的 你增加同步锚
anchor, it becomes 14, and you
它变成了 14
emit a push.
然后你发出一个推送
The Files app receives the push.
文件 App 收到推送
Your enumerator is called with
你的同步锚就被调用起来
this new function,
添加了这个新功能
enumerateChanges.
enumerateChanges
So before, it was enumerateItem,
所以 之前是 enumerateItem
and now, it's enumerateChanges.
现在是 enumerateChanges
And it's passing you the
然后 它会传递
previous sync anchor it has.
你之前的同步锚
So here it's the current
现在这里是当前的
version, it's the version 13, so
版本 版本编号 13
it's passing you 13.
它会传递给你 13
When your enumerator gets that
当你的枚举器收到
callback, it fetches the new
回调函数后 它会抓取
item, which is here, 14, the
新条目 就在这 14
item with the change number 14.
版本编号变更为 14 的条目
It sent it back to the observer,
然后它将其送回到 observer
and then it called
然后它调用
finishEnumerating up to the new
finishEnumerating 到
version here.
这里的新版本
This is 14.
这里是 14
And you don't have anymore
没有更多的变更了
change coming, so you just say,
你就可以直接用
notComing false.
notComing false
OK, and now we're ready to
我们现在就可以显示
display the update.
更新了
Oh, we forgot one thing, which
哦 我们忘了一件事
is the Files app [inaudible] the
文件 App 将会
new sync anchor.
更新为新的同步锚
So I went very fast on push
我快速讲讲
notification, and it's actually
推送通知 这个很有趣
interesting because for this
因为这次
time, the push notification
推送通知
doesn't go to your file provider
不会到你的 File Provider 扩展
extension.
那里去
It goes to the file provider
它实际上是去
daemon, actually.
File Provider 后台程序
And so when receiving your push,
当收到你的推送时
the file provider daemon is
File Provider 后台程序将
going to initiate the
启动
enumerateChanges code on your
你的枚举器上的
enumerator, and at that point,
enumerateChanges 代码
you can return the item.
然后你就可以传回条目
Another [inaudible] what you
另外有关推送我需要
have to know for push is -- and
讲解的一点就是
I will go briefly into this --
我会尽量简单点说
your PKPushType must be a
你的 PKPushType 必须是
PKPushType file provider.
一个 PKPushType 的 File Provider
The topic name is your
分组名必须是你的
bundle-identifier plus a suffix,
数据包标识符再加上一个后缀
pushkit.fileprovider.
pushkit.FileProvider
And your payload must include a
你的有效载荷一定要
container identifier, which
包括一个容器标识符
refers to one of the possible
指向有可能的枚举器
enumerator.
其中之一
For more on push notification,
有关更多推送提醒的问题
check out this session,
请查看去年的
Introduction to Notification,
Introduction to Notification
from last year.
（推送入门讲座）
So we've seen pushes, but you
我们已经讲过了推送
might ask, what if I have some
不过你有可能会问
changes and I want to tell the
如果我有些想要通知系统的变更
system about it, but I don't
但是我没有
have a push for it?
相应的一个推送该怎么办
In that case, you would want to
在这种情况下
code the file provider daemon
你需要编码 File Provider 后台程序
and just say, oh, I have a
说明
change.
变更的存在
Well, we have a function just
我们这里有个函数
for that, which is called,
就是
NSFileProvider signalChanges
NSFileProvider signalChanges
forContainer.
forContainer
When receiving such a code, the
当接收到代码后
file provider daemon is going to
File Provider 后台程序就能够
enumerate changes just like it
枚举变更 作用和
would do for pushes.
推送相同
So let me go back to that
让我讲回到
method.
这个方法
The signalChanges method, when
sinalchanges 方法
should you call it?
你该在什么时候调用呢
So first, you can tell, you can
首先 你可以
call it for the initial set of
为初始的一组文件
files.
调用它
Imagine you just installed your
想象你刚刚安装了你的
app and you already have some
应用程序 然后在 File Provider 扩展
files in your file provider
里面有一些文件
extension that you want the
你想要告知系统
system to know about.
这些文件的存在
Then, in case of changing
然后就是帐户变更的情况
account -- for instance, the
比如
user is logging out, logging in
用户登出 然后登入一个
to a new account -- you would
新的帐户 你就需要
want to tell the system to
在帐户变更后
reload after this account change
告知系统重新加载
because usually there were no
此时一般没有
pushes.
推送可用
More generally, you would want
更普遍的是 你可以对所有
to call that for any change
没有对应推送的变更使用这个方法
without a push, including the
包括在本地上
one made locally.
做出的变更
So let me go back to one thing,
我再讲回一点
which is earlier we saw that
之前我们看到
your file provider needs to
你的 File Provider 需要
implement [inaudible] providing
应用程序提供
[inaudible].
文件网址
If the file is not local at that
如果此时 文件不是
point, you need to tell the
在本地的话 你就需要
system that, well, this file is
告知系统 这个文件
not downloading.
不是正在下载
If it is, what you should do is
如果文件在本地的话
you should signal for changes in
你就应该在工作集中
the working set if the item is
进行 signalChanges 如果条目是
in the working set.
在工作集中的话
Same thing if you have an
同样的 如果你有一个
enumerator running for the
正在为母应用程序运行的枚举器
parent, you should call
你需要在
signalChanges on the
parentItemIdentifier 上调用
parentItemIdentifier.
signalChanges
Well, so under the hood, signal
所以 在后台 singalChanges
changes can be called from both
可以从你的应用程序或者
your app and your file provider
从 File Provider 扩展
extension, so it's very
进行调用
convenient.
十分方便
You must call signalChanges even
甚至对于系统引发的变更
for system-initiated changes.
你也必须要调用 signalChanges
This is exactly what I was
这就像我
describing earlier.
之前描述的一样
You could say the system could
你可以说系统能够
infer that the file has changed.
推测出文件已经发生变更
No, we don't do that.
但是不行 我们不能这么做
We let you explicitly tell us
我们需要你明白地告诉我们
that you know about this change.
你已经知道了这一变更
But don't worry about it.
但是不用担心
signalChanges is very, very
signalChanges 是特别
cheap.
易得的
So now, we've seen all these
我们已经讲完了
three topics on screen: creating
屏幕上这三个话题
the project, providing an item,
创建项目 提供一个条目
and enumerating items.
枚举条目
So now, it's time for Johannes
接下来 Johannes 会
to come on stage and cover the
上台来给大家
last topics.
讲解剩下的话题
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Pierre.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Pierre
So we've seen how to get your
那么我们已经见到如何将文件
items into the Files app or into
获取至文件 App
the document browser.
或者文件浏览器上
But of course, that is only part
当然 这只是你们
of what you are interested in
所感兴趣的一部分
doing or what your users are
或者你们用户感兴趣操作
interested in doing.
的一部分
An equally important part is
另一个同样重要的部分是
that your users are able to
你们的用户可以
modify files.
变更文件
And to modify files, there are
而且要变更文件有很多种办法
various possibilities how you
你既可以在
can modify files in the Files
文件 App 中实现
app and using other
也可以使用
technologies.
其他技术办法
So in the Files app, as an
那么以在文件 App 为例
example, bring up this menu
模拟用户
controller here as a user, and
激活菜单控制栏
this menu controller gives the
在菜单控制栏里
users a variety of options to
为用户提供了
modify files or to perform
多种变更文件
actions on files.
的操作动作
One of these actions, for
以其中一个动作
example, is the Info option
举例来说
here, and that simply brings up
是这里的信息条目
a nice Info panel.
非常简单地激活了信息面板
And that is backed by
这个信息面板中所显示的
information that you're already
信息是你已经
providing.
提供过的
That's the item method that
这个条目的操作是
you're already implementing.
你已经执行过的
Other options are, for example,
而其他条目 比如
the Share action here, and that
这里的分享动作 是由我们大家都了解的
is backed by a well-known old
老朋友
friend, the
UIActivityViewController
UIActivityViewController.
来支持的
And of course, you're able to
而且 你当然可以
simply add activities using
使用 activity plug-in 进行
activity plug-ins, and that's
简单地增加其他动作
another way for you to expose
这也是另一种在条目上
actions on these items.
显示动作的方法
But then, there are other
另外 还有一些其他的潜在条目
possible options that are not
在目前现有的
backed by any existing system UI
UI 系统中
so far.
没有支持
For example, renaming items.
比如说 重命名条目
Renaming items brings up a nice
重命名条目在文件 App 中激活了
UI in the Files app, but we're
一个漂亮的 UI 界面 但是我们
not so far exposing a way to
目前还没有发布
actually tell you about the
一个关于重命名的
rename.
完整内容
And that is what this part of
这个内容 就是这部分议程中
the session is about.
将要说明的
To back a rename or something
为了支持重命名或其他类似的功能
like that, we expose a wide
我们发布了多种条目
variety of options, and these
这些条目包括
options are moving files around,
移动文件
creating files -- for example,
创建文件 举个例子
if you, if the user hits the
比如你 或用户们
little + button, that shows up
点击文件浏览控制页面上的
in the document browser view
“+”小按钮
controller, or if the user drag
又比如用户将文件
and drops a file into the Files
拖动至文件 App
app or into the document browser
或者是其他应用程序的
in another application.
文件浏览页面
Last but not least, modifying
最后但同样重要的是 变更文件
attributes on files.
的属性
So if the user performs a
因此如果用户进行
tagging operation or looks at a
标签操作 或者查看了文件
file and thus wants to modify
之后想要变更文件的
the last use date of the file.
上一次使用日期
And all of these are actions
这些
that are backed by, that back
用户动作
user operations.
都是被支持的
And you are, your extension is
而你的扩展
implementing these.
就是实现这些功能
All right, so that is awfully
好吧 这些确实
abstract, so let's have a look
很抽象 那么我们就看一看
at one of these actions and how
其中的功能之一 以及你
you implement it.
如何将其实现
All right, and as our example,
好的 来看我们举的这个例子
we're going to use the Import
我们将要使用
Document action.
导入文稿功能
But all of the actions are
然而所有的功能
actually implemented in a very
在实现的时候 所使用的方法
similar way.
都是相似的
The Import Document action is a
标签操作功能很好用
nice one because it deals with a
因为它是使用在新文件上的
new file, but most of these
但是这些大多数的功能
actions are kind of similar.
都是差不多的
They have slightly different
它们在特性上只有
parameters and, of course, have
很少的不同 并且当然在
slightly different semantics,
语义上也略有不同
but everything I'm going to tell
但是我在这部分
you in this session is going to
要讲的内容
count for pretty much all of the
是对几乎所有的功能都
actions.
适用的
So the Import Document action
导入文稿功能是这样
works this way.
工作的
The system gives you an existing
系统给你一个现有的文件的 URL
file URL, so that's a file on
那么这是一个磁盘上的文件
disk, and this file is any
系统给你的这个文件
location that the system gives
可以是任何地址的
you, it's possibly in the Temp
可能是在临时文件夹里
folder or wherever the
或者也有可能是随便一个应用程序里
application that, for example,
比如说
performs a create operation
执行了一个创建动作
stores its templates, but in any
保存了模板不管是什么情况
case, this file is basically for
这个文件是给你
you to use.
使用的
You can go and move this file
你可以将这个文件
into your file provider storage.
移动至你的 File Provider 存储空间里
So this is, this file is now
那么这个文件就在你的
under your control.
控制之内了
It's in your container.
因为它在你的 container 中
At this point, you need to
这时 你需要
schedule a background upload so
安排后台上传
that this file from your
这样你的 container 中的文件
container actually gets uploaded
才可以上传到
into your cloud.
你的云端
And last but not least, you call
最后但同样重要的是 你要调用
the completion handler.
完成处理器
This is very important, and this
这非常重要
is a very important part of
而且也是这个流程中非常重要的
this.
部分
We just scheduled a background
我们刚刚安排了一个
upload, but we did not wait for
后台上传业务 但是我们没有等到
the background upload to finish
后台上传完成后
until we call the completion
再调用
handler.
完成处理器
So the file is actually being
那么文件实际上正在
uploaded in the background,
后台上传中
meaning that the user does not
意味着用户不需要
have to wait for this file to be
一定得等到
actually fully uploaded until
文件真正上传完成后
you tell the system, hey, I got
再调用系统
this.
“嘿我上传完成啦”
I've got this file under my
对于用户来讲 我已经把文件
control.
在我控制之下了
I'll scheduled the upload.
我已经安排了后台上传了
This file will be in the cloud
这份文件将在某个时间
at some point.
上传到云端
So the user doesn't have to wait
那么用户就不必等着
for this upload of the file that
文件上传完成
can be potentially many
有时候文件可能有
megabytes.
几百兆
So that's how the general flow
这就是
of this looks.
一般的流程
Let's have a look at how the
我们来看一看
data flow of this operation
这个流程中的数据流
looks.
是怎样的
So as I said, the initial
就像我说的 这个执行动作的
impetus for this operation is
发起初始是
that the user created, or
用户创建
pasted, or dropped a file into
或者粘贴 或者拖动一个文件
the, into a container in your
到你的 File Provider 中的
file provider.
container
And at that point, the Import
这时导入文稿针对
Document action on your file
你的 File Provider 的
provider extension subclass gets
扩展子类别被
called.
调用
You make a database entry.
你创建了一个数据库入口
You make sure that the file is
你确认文件正在被
getting uploaded.
上传
So you schedule the upload.
所以你安排了上传动作
Now, we're done, right?
现在 我们完成了 对不对
We can call the
我们可以调用
completionHandler.
完成处理器
But as Pierre has told, the
但正如皮埃尔提到的
system does not automatically
系统不会自动
infer that this file basically
推断 文件已经被
has changed.
变更了
So one important bit here is
所以这里重要的一点是
that you at this point signal us
你在这一步要给我们发出信号
to tell us, hey, there are
告诉我们 嘿 这个 container
changes on this container.
发生改变了
We need to re-enumerate this
我们需要重新枚举
container.
这个 container
This is important so that the
这很重要 是为了保证
user gets immediate feedback.
用户获得即刻的反馈
So the next step is actually
所以下一步就是
that you tell us there are
你来告诉我们
changes here.
这里发生变化了
And at that point, we simply
那么在这一步 我们就简单
make a note.
做一个记录
We say, OK, for this container
我们记下 OK 这个 container
-- and keep in mind, the user is
并记在心里 用户有可能
probably looking at this
正在查看这个
container, right?
container 对不对
They just hit the little +
他们刚刚点击了那里的
button there.
“+”小按钮
Of course, they hit the + button
当然了 他们正在查看 container
in the container that they're
并点击了“+”按钮
looking at, so they want to see
那么他们想要看
these changes.
这些变更
So you told the system, changes
所以你会告诉系统
are pending.
变更正在执行中
Now, you tell the system, call
现在你告诉系统
the completionHandler.
调用完成处理器
We're done with this operation.
我们已经完成了这个执行动作
The system gets unblocked.
系统已经打开
And at this point, the system
这时 系统可以
can go and call, turn around,
启动并调用 回溯
and enumerate changes.
并枚举所做的变更
You tell us, sweet, we just
你告诉我们 嘿 我们刚刚
added this item, and it's now
增加了这个条目 现在有可能
uploading, probably.
正在上传
And you return the changed item
你将变更过的条目 作为变更集合的一部分
to us as part of a change set.
回传给我们
And we can update our UI and
我们就可以升级 UI
show a little uploading error in
并在条目的角落显示一点点
the corner of the item.
上传中发生的错误
So the user gets immediate
因此用户可以获得即时反馈
feedback that their data is safe
在你的云端上 他们的信息
in your cloud.
是安全的
So let me reiterate that.
那么让我再重申一下
Operations are expected to
执行动作是应
finish immediately, and thus,
立刻完成的
you need to defer long-running
那么因此你需要延迟需要长期运行的
tasks, such as uploads, to the
任务 比如使用 NSURLSession
background using NSURLSession.
上传到后台
So now, we've got this item
那么现在 这个条目正在被上传中
uploading, and that's great,
这很好
but, of course, at some point,
但是 在一些情况下
this upload is going to finish
当上传即将完成的时候
and we want to tell the user
我们想要告诉用户
about the new status of the
文件的最新
file.
状态
So let's go into that.
让我们进入到这个部分
The way that works is that
这一部分工作的方法是
NSURLSession at some point will
NSURLSession 在某种时刻下会注意到
notice, hey, this upload
嘿 这个上传
succeeded.
成功了
Sweet, the item is in the cloud.
很好 这个项目已经在云端了
And the way this, the way
而 NSURLSession
NSURLSession tells you about
告诉你这些的方法
that is that it calls a
被称为
callback, an NSURLSession
回调 在你母应用程序上的
background callback, on your
一个 NSURLSession
parent application.
后台回调
Your parent application at this
这时 你的母应用程序可以
point can go and update the
去上传
database entry.
数据库入口
It sets a little flag in your
它会在你的数据库里
database that says, this file is
设置标记 提示这个文件已经
uploaded.
上传
It's no longer [inaudible] on
它已经不再
disk.
位于磁盘上
Our upload succeeded.
上传已经成功
We don't have to retry this
我们不必再次执行上传
upload.
动作
And we should inform the user
并且我们应该通知用户
that this upload is finished.
上传已经完成
So as Pierre mentioned, the
正如 Pierre 提到的
signalChanges method can be
这个用信号提示变更的方法既可以被
called both by your extension
你的扩展调用
and the parent application, and
也可以被母应用程序调用 并且我们为你
this is why.
解释了原因
Now, you tell us there are
这时 你告诉我们 这个 container 里面
changes on this container.
发生了变更
And at this point, the same old
那么 与先前同样的流程
dance happens.
开始启动
The system notes that changes
系统通知变更正在进行
are pending, it re-enumerates
并重新枚举你的
your, the, your working set, and
工作集 而且这时
at this point, you can return
你可以从你的 File Provider 扩展
in, from your file provider
获取到这个条目已经被完整地上传
extension that this item is
使用的是
properly uploaded using the
NSFileProviderItem 协议中的密钥
isUploaded key on the
并将这个信息
NSFileProviderItem protocol.
回传
Now, sometimes uploads fail.
有时候 上传文件会失败
For example, your server might
比如 你的服务器会告诉我们
tell us, hey, this user is out
这个用户超出了云端存储
of quota.
限额
And in this situation, the same
这种情况下 基本上与先前同样的
dance happens, basically.
流程开始启动
So NSURLSession D is going to
NSURLSession D 要告诉
tell your parent application,
你的母应用程序
hey, this upload failed.
嘿 这个上传失败了
That's too bad.
真麻烦
You're going to have to handle
你总得去解决
this somehow.
这个问题
So again, we make a database
那么又一次 我们打开数据库
entry.
入口
We signal the system.
我们通知系统
The system notes that changes
系统标记变更正在
are pending.
进行中
The system re-enumerates.
系统重新枚举
And we can return the updated
我们可以回传更新的
item.
条目
Now, this updated item should
现在 这个更新的条目应该
reflect the fact that this item
反映出目前其正处于
is now in an error state, so to
错误状态的事实
turn an update error, an upload
所以一个更新的错误 上传了的错误
error that is reflecting what
会反映出目前真正在发生的
actually here.
内容
All right, let's get into a bit
那么 我们来更进一步
more detail.
更详细一点
As I said, you mark the item as
正如我说的 你通过上传的条目特性
being in an error status by
中的错误特性
using the upload error property
来标记其处于
on the item properties.
错误状态
You signal re-enumeration so
你发出重新枚举的信号
that the user can see that this
用户就可以看到
item's in an error state.
这个条目处于错误状态
And then, how you actually
然后 你如何处理这个
continue in this error state
错误状态
depends completely on the kind
取决于你正在查看的
of error that you're looking at.
错误类型
So some, not all errors are the
有一些 并不是所有的错误
same thing.
都是同一种类型
There's the possibility that
有一种可能是
you're running into an
你遇见了一种
intermittent error.
间歇性的错误
For example, the user was, I
比如 我也不清楚 用户可能
don't know, camping out in the
在森林里野营了
jungle for two weeks, and
两个星期 然后
NSURLSession D just gave up
NSURLSession D 已经放弃了
because there was no Wi-Fi, no
因为没有 WiFi
wireless connection.
没有网络链接
In this situation, the easiest
在这种情况下 最简单的
thing to do is tell the user,
办法就是告诉用户
hey, your data wasn't uploaded,
嘿 你的数据没有上传成功
but we're on it.
但我们正在处理
We re-enqueue the, your
我们重新排列了你的
NSURLSession task.
NSURLSession 任务
We still mark this item as being
我们仍然会将这个条目标记为
in an error state, as not being
错误状态 因为它没有
up to date in the cloud, but we
上传到云端 但我们仍会
simply retry.
继续尝试
There's nothing that the user
用户没有什么必须要做
has to do.
的事情
In the error description, you
在错误描述里 你或许可以
can possibly tell the user, hey,
告诉用户 嘿
maybe go online or something
你可以上网或类似的什么事
like that, but that's pretty
但能做的也就是
much it.
这么多了
There's also the possibility
还有一种可能是
that you're running into a
你遇到了持续性的错误
persistent error, and that is
而且还是
different.
不同的
In a persistent error case,
在持续性错误状态的情况下
like, for example, the user's
比如说
out of quota, what you need to
用户的云端存储配额用尽 你需要
do is tell the user, hey, you're
告诉用户 嘿 你的存储配额
out of quota.
用光了
You got to go and buy more quota
你得去买点我们网页上的
on our web page.
存储空间
And in that situation, basically
在那种情况下 基本上
what you give us is a, an error
你要给我们的是 一个
that suggests a recovery option.
伴随着建议恢复选项的错误提示
Now, last but not least, there's
最后但也是重要的一个可能
the possibility for
就是遇到坚定错误
authentication errors, and these
而且这些
are kind of special.
比较特别
The user has to do something
用户必须要对你的应用程序
specific to your application.
做一些特定的设置
For example, re-authenticate.
比如说 重新鉴定
Well, that's actually the only
这或许是
possibility in that situation,
这种情况下唯一可以进行的
probably.
操作
And for that possibility, a
对于这种可能的情况
custom action will be called by
系统会调用一个
the system.
顾客操作
So what's a custom action?
什么是顾客操作
Well, conveniently, that's our
简单讲 那是我们的
next section, and let's have a
下一个部分我们来看一看
look at, back at this menu view
回到这个菜单视图
controller here, menu controller
控制器 这里的这个菜单
here.
控制器
We've seen these system-provided
我们已经看过了这些系统提供的
actions here, and the way these
操作 它们只所以能够运行
work is that the user just taps
就是因为当用户点击它们时
them and is backed by an action
就会有一个内部由你的 Provider
that is internally backed by
支持的指令
your provider.
来支持它们的运行
But we also offer another
不过 我们也给大家提供机会
opportunity for you to customize
来定制它 也就是
this, which is to introduce a
在这种情况下
custom action in this situation.
引入一个顾客操作
So that's a action, and this one
这就是一个操作 在幻灯片上
here is called Custom on the
它的名字就是 Custom
slide, but it can be whatever
不过你可以把它改成任何
name you want.
你想要的名字
And the way this works is that
它是这样运行的
you expose an operation, a UI
你公开一个操作 一个 UI
operation, that is scoped to
操作 它是适配你的
your file provider extension.
File Provider 扩展范围的
You provide an interface for
你为这个操作提供一个
this operation that is backed by
界面 一个由一种新 UI 扩展
a new type of UI extension.
支持的界面
And this is a separate process
这是另一个在系统上运行的
that's running on the system,
独立的进程
and it's backed by a subclass of
它是由 FPUIActionExtension
FPUIActionExtension
ViewController
ViewController.
支持的
So how do we do that?
那么 我们怎么做到这点呢
Well, first of all, we list the
首先 我们在我们的扩展中的
possible number of actions in
info.plist 上
the info.plist of our extension,
列举出操作可能的数量
and this is really easy.
这点是很容易的
We have an action name, we have
我们有一个操作的名字
an identifier, and we have an
有一个标识符
activation rule.
还有一个激活准则
And this activation rule is used
这个激活准则就是要搞清楚
to figure out which of these
哪些操作是适用于
actions applies to which items.
哪些条目的
So in this example on the slide,
在幻灯片上的这个例子
we're simply using a true
我们只是简单使用了一个真谓词
predicate, which means that this
这意味着这个操作
action is, that every item in
你的 Provider 的每一个条目
your provider's eligible for
相对于这个特定的操作
this specific action.
都是合格的
But you can basically go wild on
但是你可以自由地
this.
对其改动
You can expose different keys on
你可以在你的条目上展示
your items and use these for
不同的 Key 然后用其来在
matching in your activation
你的激活准则中
rule.
进行匹配
So how does this work?
这是如何运作的呢
Well, the user long presses on
用户在文件 App 或者
an item in the Files app or in
文稿浏览器中
the document browser, and at
长按一个条目
this point, we consult the
此时 我们去查阅其
index, not your extension.
索引 而不是你的扩展
We don't even bring that up.
我们甚至都不会调用它
We consult the index of the item
我们去查询你之前
that you previously returned to
转回给我们条目的
us.
索引
We look at the attributes and we
我们查看其属性
match this predicate against the
然后用谓词
attributes.
和属性进行匹配
At this point, we know whether
此时 我们知道
this predicate returns a yes or
这个谓词将返回的是 是
a no, and we can simply display
或是否 如果返回的是 是
the action if it returns a yes.
我们就可以直接显示操作
OK, so now, the user sees this
现在 用户看到了这个操作
action, and probably they tap on
很有可能
it.
他们会点击它
So the user taps on the action.
用户点击这个操作
What happens now?
现在发生什么呢
Well, we bring up your UI
我们调用你的 UI 扩展
extension, and your UI extension
你的 UI 扩展被
gets a call to its
调用后进行 prepareForaction
prepareForAction method.
运作
What this gets, what this does
在这一步
is it, we hand it a set of items
我们其实就是提供带有 actionIdentifier 的
plus the actionIdentifier that
一套条目 它实际是用户选择的
the user actually chose, and you
然后你就可以
can go and present whatever UI
对这一操作
you have for this action.
显示你现有的 UI
You return from this method.
然后从这个方法返回
We present your view controller.
我们给你展示视图控制器
It slides up nicely in the Files
它很漂亮的在
app.
文件 App 中向上滑动
And that's it.
这就行了
At this point, you know which
此时 你知道你进行操作
items you're performing these
作用到的条目
actions on.
都是哪些
For example, and you can do
比如 你可以
whatever is necessary to perform
做一切有必要的行为来
these actions.
运行这些操作
And these actions are completely
而且 这些操作也是完全定制的
custom, so, of course, it's
当然 具体上
completely up to you what is
会发生什么
happening here.
都取决于你的行为
At some point, the user will be
在这个阶段 用户
done with this action.
应该已经完成了这个操作
Maybe you're implementing a Done
你可能会执行一个完成
button.
按钮
Maybe this is, there's some
也许就这样
natural end to this action.
这个操作完成后是一个自然的终止
But at any rate, you call the
不过无论如何 你都要在扩展
completeRequest method on the
的环境中 调用 completeRequest
extension context, and the
然后系统将
system simply dismisses your UI.
不再接受你的 UI
But that's just custom actions.
这仅仅是顾客操作
As I promised earlier, there's a
我之前许诺要讲解的
special case for authentication
验证操作
actions, so look at that.
是一个特殊情况 请看这个
called exactly the same way as
通过顾客 UI 操作一模一样的方法
custom UI actions are called,
被调用
except they're called in a
但是它们是在一个
special case, and that's when
特殊情况下被调用的
you to us return an
这就是当你返回给我们一个
authentication error.
验证错误的情况
So if you return an
如果你转回给我们一个
authentication error, what
验证错误
happens is that we call the
我们将会调用
prepareForAuthentication method
prepareForAuthentication
on your FPUI extension,
就在你的 FPUI 扩展
ActionExtensionViewController.
ActionExtensionViewController 上调用
And everything from there on
从这儿开始
flows just the same way.
一切就按照相同的方法运行了
You call, you can call, you can
你可以调用
display whatever UI is necessary
你可以为验证
for authenticating.
展示任何必需的 UI
At some point, the user has
在一些情况下 用户
authenticated.
已经经过认证了
You can call the dismiss method,
你就可以使用取消方法
the view controller dismisses,
视图控制器就会停止处理
and you're now authenticated,
你现在就经过认证了
and we will simply retry.
然后我们就重新操作即可
So those are actions, and those
这些操作
are very nice, but all said and
确实很棒 不过尽管说了
done, they are only showing up
这么多 它们只出现在
in the, either the document
文稿浏览器的视图控制器
browser view controller or the
或者是
Files app.
文件 App 里
And that is great.
这很棒
That is a great way for you to
这个方法很棒 能够使你
expose something to your user,
给你的用户展示一些东西
but sometimes you need something
但是有时候
more, and for that, we have this
你可能有更多需求 对于这点
concept of Services.
我们就提出了服务这个概念
What's a Service?
什么是服务
Well, as I said, there's caveats
正如我说过的 对于顾客操作
for the custom actions.
有很多值得注意的地方
But sometimes you need
但是有些时候
programmatic access to specific
一些特定的文件
files.
需要编程访问
And if you're currently
比如说你正在
publishing an SDK, for example,
发布一个 SDK
this is where you export,
这就是你能够
expose, where you can expose the
展示你的 SDK 正在展示
same functionality that your SDK
的功能
is currently exposing.
的所在
Services are a way for you to
服务可以帮你直接
expose functionality directly on
在一个条目上展示功能
an item, so let's have a look at
我们来看一下
how that goes.
它是如何运作的
First, you need to define what
首先 你需要定义
your service is.
你的服务是什么
And at the base level, a service
从最基本上讲
is simply a name that's an
一个服务就是一个名字
identifier that you give the
这个名字是你赋予这个服务的标识符
service plus an Objective-C
再加上一个 Objective-C
protocol.
协议
And this is basically any old
基本上任何老的
Objective-C protocol.
Objective-C 协议都可以
There's some caveats here that
我们很快就会
we'll go into real soon.
讲一讲要格外注意的地方
The protocol must be known to
这个协议必须是
you and to the developer that's
你和使用它的开发人员
using it.
都知晓的
So both of you need to determine
所以 你们二者需要决定
what the protocol is.
使用哪个协议
And this is because the
这是因为
developer using this is going to
使用它的开发人员将会
perform method calls on an
对你展示的对象
object that is exposed by you,
进行有效的
effectively.
方法调用
So if the signatures don't
如果签名不匹配的话
match, nothing will happen.
就没有办法运行
This will just result in an
结果只会出现
error.
错误
And when I say they're
当我说它们会进行
performing method calls, the way
方法调用时
this works is actually that this
我的意思是它们将会通过 NSXPC
is implemented using NSXPC,
来进行运作
which is a great technology for
这是一项针对进程间通讯
interprocess communication.
的伟大技术
And that means that the usual
这也就是意味着平常的
XPC rules apply.
XPC 规则也适用
So all the parameters that are
所以 所有通过
passed through this protocol
这个协议的参数都
have to be secure codable.
必须能够被安全编码
And of course, the classes have
当然 所有的类别
to be available in both your
也必须能够在你的扩展
extension and the app that's
和进行方法调用的 App
calling this.
上找的到
And you cannot directly return
你不能直接从这个协议
any objects from this protocol.
回传任何对象
So you have to return, if you
如果你不得不回传
want to return something, you
一些东西的话
have to call back via completion
你必须通过 Completion block
block.
来进行
Now, the rules for this are
关于这个的规则
somewhat interesting, and
是很有趣的
there's, was a session in 2012
在 2012 年有一次讲座
that goes into way more detail
很细致地进行了讲解
than I can go, possibly go into
比我今天在这里
here today.
能够大家讲的细致的多
So I encourage you to have a
我建议大家
look at that session.
去看看那一次的讲座
All right, let's quickly go
好的 我们接下来快速看一下
through the data flow that is
这里会发生的数据流
happening here because that is,
因为这点
that warrants having a look at.
还是值得大家一看的
Your third-party application
你的第三方应用程序
goes and basically inquires on
启动并且
an URL, what are the services
查询一个网址 有什么服务
that are exposed on this URL?
能够显示在这个网址上呢
And at this point, your
此时 你的扩展受到调用
extension gets a call to answer,
来进行答复
hey, what are the supported
嘿 这个条目上有
services on this item?
哪些支持的服务呢
It returns an array of service
它将会回传一批服务的来源
sources, and a service source is
一个服务的来源并不是
not a service itself.
服务本身
It's an object that can create a
它是一个能够有效
service, effectively, that can
创建服务的对象
create an XPC listener endpoint.
可以创建一个 XPC 端点侦听器
We return these services as
我们将这些服务
services to the application.
回传给应用程序
So on the service object, the
所以在服务对象上
application can go and then
应用程序可以
create a proxy object.
创建一个代理对象
Let's have a look at that, how
我们来看一下
that works.
这是怎么样运行的
So the third-party application
第三方应用程序
uses that service after it's
在查找完可用的服务
looked at which services are
之后 开始使用
available.
其中的一个服务
Of course, they can be any
当然 可能不只是一个服务
number of services, right?
而是任意数量的 对吧
So it looks at the identifiers
它先查看一下这些服务
of these services, figures out
的标识符决定
which one it wants to use, and
想要使用哪一个
creates a messenger.
然后创建一个 Messenger
At this point, we are asking
此时 我们让
your extension on the service
你在服务来源上的扩展
source to make a listener
建立一个
endpoint.
端点侦听器
So it returned that.
然后它回传了这个
A ListenerEndpoint, that's an
ListenerEndpoint
existing NSXPC class, although
是一个已有的 NSXPC 类别 尽管
it's currently only exposed on
目前它只能在
macOS.
macOS 上显示
We're now bringing it to iOS.
我们现在也将其移植到 iOS 上
At this point, the third-party
此时 第三方应用程序
application can grab the remote
能够在 Messenger 上获得
proxy on this messenger, and
远程代理
that calls on your listener
然后调用你的侦听器
delegate the
委托进行
shouldAcceptConnection callback.
shouldAcceptConnection 回调
At this point, you can call, you
此时 你可以调用
can configure this connection
可以配置这个连接
and return this connection to
然后将其回传至
the system.
系统
So in this case, for example,
在这个情况下
you provide a proxy object that
比如你提供一个代理对象
is being exported by our
正在被我们的扩展
extension.
导出
And from there on out, we can go
然后从这里开始
and call whatever methods are
我们就可以在第三方应用程序的
defined in our protocol on this
远程代理对象上
remote proxy object in our
调用协议中的
third-party application.
任何方法
And all of these calls will be
所有的这些调用都将
translated into calls in our
被解读成我们的扩展
extension.
中的调用
This is a, an extremely powerful
这是一个很强大的机制
mechanism for you to expose
能够帮助你
basically any old possible SDK
在你的扩展上显示
operations on your extension.
任何老的 SDK 操作
As a, as an aside, we don't
当然了 说句离题的话
expect everyone to implement
我们并不期望大家都使用这个
this, and it's perfectly fine if
如果你的初版没有使用
your first version does not use
这个机制
this mechanism at all.
也是完全没有问题的
This is a very advanced topic,
这是一个很高阶的话题
so if you only, if all you
只要你能够
implement is enumeration and the
使用枚举
usual file provider actions,
和平常的 File Provider  操作
we're already super happy.
我们就已经快欣喜若狂了
All right.
好的
Let's summarize what we've seen
我们来总结一下
today.
今天讲的内容
We've seen what a file provider
我们知道了什么是一个
is, and how we can use a file
File Provider
provider to back the
知道了如何用 File Provider 支持
enumerations in the Files app,
文件 App 中的枚举
and how to use it to show files
以及如何使用它在
in the document browser.
文稿浏览器中显示文件
We've seen how you use
我们讲过了
enumerations to expose items to
如何利用枚举
both of these controls and how
来展示这二者
you can enumerate the working
如何枚举工作集
set, how you can enumerate
如何枚举
changes to the working set, and
工作集发生的变更
how you can push changes to the
以及如何将这些变更推送到
working set.
工作集
And finally, we've seen how you
最后 我们也谈了
can implement actions to modify
如何使用操作来
stuff in your hierarchy and how
修改你的结构层次
you can then go even further,
然后更进一步
and customize these actions, and
定制这些操作
even implement services that are
甚至使用完全
completely custom to your
根据你的 Provider 定制的
provider, and expose those to
服务然后将其
third-party apps.
展示给第三方应用程序
For more information, we have a
如果各位需要更多的信息 我们在
page on the developer.apple.com
developer.apple.com 有讲解
and we have a list of related
我们还有一系列的会议
sessions that go into way more
比我们能够在今天
detail than we can possibly do
给大家讲的使用
here on some of the technologies
各种技术的信息
used.
要细致的多
And with that, I hope you are
好了 我祝愿
having a great conference.
大家与会愉快
Thank you very much.
十分感谢大家
[ Applause ]
[掌声]